MICHAEL JACOBS

http://mjacobs.me hi@mjacobs.me

Design generalist with solid programming skills, an entrepreneurial background, and an interest in leadership. Experience bringing web and mobile software products from concept to market to scale since 2007. Passionate about art, music, and building a more equitable future. Portfolio and references available upon request.

EDUCATION

Y-Combinator

Summer 2007 Incubator for Hello, Chair

University of Arizona

2003-2007

Studied Computer Science and Music Composition

SKILLS

Design Skills

- User experience design
 - Interaction design
 - User interface design
 - Data visualization
 - Prototyping
 - Wireframing
 - User testing
- Product management
- Music composition, production, sound design

Engineering Skills

- Javascript (React, D3)
- HTML, CSS
- · React Native, Swift
- Python

EXPERIENCE

Promise Networks

Oakland, CA

Lead Designer / Engineer

Jan 2018 - July 2019

Promise aims to create an equitable and humane alternative to incarceration by using updated technology to facilitate better human connectivity, focused on providing support and care to people who are involved with the criminal justice system. As Promise's second employee, I helped bring multiple web and mobile products from concept to reality, doing much of the research and design, as well as majorly contributing to front-end engineering and sales support efforts.

Uber Technologies

San Francisco, CA & NYC, NY Feb 2013 - April 2017

Lead UX Designer / Engineer

Contributed design and code to many different parts of the company, especially: internal tools, and the rider and driver apps. Helped define Uber's design culture and grow the team from 5 to around 200 designers.

- Became Uber's first Design Engineer; helped evolve the Design team's process to utilize prototyping and user testing.
- Designed a major feature in the Rider app which allowed city operations teams to communicate with riders.
- Co-led the launch of UberPool: conceptualized, designed, prototyped, tested, launched, and refined the UberPool product. Received a patent for the UberPool UI.
- Brought design to the Uber Data team; designed and engineered many
 of the internal data visualization tools that gave city operations teams
 and executives insight into business performance.
- Led design and product management on the Observability Applications team in NYC. Researched, designed, and oversaw the building of reporting, monitoring, and alerting tools to help internal developers ensure the reliability and efficiency of Uber's back-end systems.

Hello, Chair, Inc.

San Francisco, CA

Co-Founder, Designer, etc.

May 2007 - April 2012

Co-founded Hello Chair with the goal of applying cutting edge machine learning to solve a variety of problems in internet ad targeting and product recommendations—notably App Store discoverability. Responsibilities included: design, front-end development, accounting, marketing, hiring, managing, and many of the other odds and ends involved in running a small software startup. Hello Chair was lucky enough to have been backed by an amazing group of investors, including: Y-Combinator, Mitch Kapor, Chris Sacca and Harrison Metal.